[Music]
Ronald G Wayne born May 17
1934 in the midst of the Great
[Music]
Depression jobs had this Focus once he
got an idea in his head that was it and
you never wanted to be between him and
where he wanted to go you'd wind up with
footprints on your forehead this is the
contract that I personally typed up he
regarded me as something of a a minor
Mentor because I was somewhat more
diplomatic than he was there was a
problem he was having at that time with
Steve osnc I said bring him over the
house we'll sit down we'll chat and it
took me 45 minutes certainly less than
an hour to get him to understand no you
can't do it that way for a business
Enterprise
okay fine he bought into it he
understood and at that moment in time
Steve Jobs says we are going to form a
[Music]
company 12 days later I went down to the
regis's office and have my name taken
off the contract
[Music]
if the company goes puff we are
individually liable for the debts of the
company well jobs and wnc didn't have
two nickel to rub together I had a house
and a bank account and a car and I was
reachable some months later I get this
letter in the mail with a check for
$1,500 I believe it was
$1,500 and the letter says all you got
to do is uh uh sign away every possible
interest you could have in the Apple
computer company and uh uh the check is
yours well I figured that I had already
done that as far as I was concerned it
was found money you know so I went ahead
and I
signed I was surprised to learn that
Steve Jobs was looking for a mentor I
wouldn't have thought him the type to be
into any sort of constructive criticism
from what I read of him I agree people
must be fascinated by Steve Jobs and
just what he was like and should be he
was a fascinating man who made Apple
what it
was obviously Jobs's technique all right
was jobs a nice guy in many ways no but
that doesn't matter that's not what
we're talking about we're talking about
what did it take to make apple what it
was
I think people will watch this m and
they'll say
surely as Ron's about to go to sleep you
must often think of what could have been
with apple I mean do you I knew exactly
what would have been if I had stayed
with a company uh I would have wound up
heading a very large documentation
department at the back of the building
shuffling papers for the next 20 years
of my life and that was not the future
that I saw for myself find some
something that you enjoy doing so much
that you'd be willing to do it for
nothing and you'll never work a day in
your life
[Music]